Contact

samin942@gmail.com

www.linkedin.com/in/shaheeramin-449243150 (LinkedIn)

Top Skills

Engineering
English
Communication

Shaheer Amin

Operations Engineer at Nayatel Pakistan

Summary

I am an adaptable college graduate (BSc Electrical Engineering) from UET Peshawar and currently at Nayatel as an Operations Engineer and have been working side by side with some of the best Engineers in the country. I am the team lead at Systems, NGN, Video and NSS departments in the Nayatel's Peshawar Branch.

During the course of my academic career, I also managed to accrue nearly 4 months of work experience. I had the privilege of working for PESCO and QRI Construction (PVT) Ltd. Renewable Energy & Engineering Services in an Intern Engineer role in my free time, where I learned valuable professional skills such as product innovation, project costing and project planning.

In both my academic and professional life, I have been consistently praised as detail-oriented by my professors and peers. Whether working on academic, extracurricular, or professional projects, I apply proven leadership, research and teamwork skills.

Being the President of IEEE UET Peshawar Student Branch, I polished my skills as a leader and learned to handle pressure situations. I was tested continuously and my patience played a key role in the success of IEEE 2019-2020 Tenure. My interpersonal skills improved greatly during this time which are essential to any organization.

Experience

Nayatel

1 year

Operations Engineer February 2022 - Present (2 months)

Peshawar, Khyber Pakhtunkhwa, Pakistan

Network Support Engineer

June 2021 - February 2022 (9 months)

Islamabad, Islāmābād, Pakistan

- Provided technical support to customers related to all FTTH issues they faced.
- Handled internet, video and POTs services.
- Maintained a positive, emphatic and professional attitude towards customers at all times.
- Responded promptly to customer inquiries and interacted with them to provide world-class solutions.
- Highlighted critical areas and improvised accordingly to cultivate desired results.
- Worked with developers and technology to ensure services are aligned as per the business needs.
- Worked closely with colleagues and supervisors to maintain a good working relationship.

Trainee Network Support Engineer April 2021 - June 2021 (3 months)

Islāmābād, Pakistan

- Underwent intensive 6-week training program and passed all exams with distinction.
- Trained in NGN, Core, Access, Transmission, Systems, Wi-Fi, VAS and other departmental courses.
- Completed 185 hours of training in total.
- Spent 4 weeks in TAC to handle customer gueries after training.

QRI Construction (PVT) Ltd. Renewable Energy & Engineering Services

Solar Intern Engineer

July 2020 - September 2020 (3 months)

Peshawar, Khyber Pakhtunkhwa, Pakistan

- Trained in system construction and maintenance.
- Provided assistance to engineers with design and drafting assistance using AutoCAD Electrical.
- Designed customized Solar PV data acquisition systems including weather station.
- Visited sites to measure roof dimensions, obstacles location.
- Prepared accurate and detailed electrical drawing sets for system installation.

WAPDA

Engineer Intern

July 2018 - September 2018 (3 months)

Peshawar, Khyber Pakhtunkhwa, Pakistan

- Experience in power and facilities infrastructure industry as well as in Electronic Power Circuit Design.
- Knowledge of maintenance of power systems, diesel generator backup power systems and fire safety systems.
- Steep knowledge of Motor controls, VFD and UPS Backups as well as of charging batteries.
- Familiarity with AC & DC power supply development and of off-line power supplies.
- Good knowledge of electrical circuits.
- Drafted report on Grid Station.

Education

University of Engineering & Technology Peshawar Bachelors, Electrical Engineering (2016 - 2020)

Edwardes College Peshawa F.Sc, Pre-Engineering · (2013 - 2015)

Fazaia Degree School and College, Peshawar Matriculation, Science · (2011 - 2013)